<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nosound</title>
    <description>digitized thoughts.</description>
    <link>http://glidesu.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://glidesu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>EVO Training - Week 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts while training for EVO: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which matchups give me the most trouble?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How many of my victories can I account to pure knowledge and execution?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of player is this person?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there a better option than this move?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the common tendencies observed across multiple players
playing the same character?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you actually have a target in mind while practicing, it becomes 
much clearer what you want to work on. The pressure to meet the demands
of a big tournament only accelerate improvement. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://glidesu.github.io/2014/06/06/EVO_Training_Week_2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://glidesu.github.io/2014/06/06/EVO_Training_Week_2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EVO Training - Week 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While this is not my first EVO event, it is my first time seriously preparing
for one. I will participate only in BlazBlue but I will more than likely
pick up USF4 and compete in future Street Fighter events. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is dedicated to logging my progress regarding BBCP training in
preparation for EVO. I have a little over one month to target specific areas
of my play that present obvious weaknesses and improve upon those areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1&quot;&gt;Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shaky start for training. Had to experiment when I was the most alert so I
could analyze my matches with my full attention and focus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weekdays&quot;&gt;Weekdays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:00 &amp;gt; Review replays marked for analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:30 &amp;gt; Training mode. Investigate issues related to notes taken from
        replay analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;08:00 &amp;gt; Prepare for Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;19:00 &amp;gt; Home from Work. Eat dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;21:00 &amp;gt; Netplay. Save replays that contain issues worth exploring.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:00 &amp;gt; Sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, there are significantly less players online. Therefore 
it is the perfect time for me to watch replays, take notes, and grind out
answers in training mode. I have to stop at 08:00 since I have to prepare for work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I am at work, I squeeze any downtime I have into watching match videos
or look up any additional information that I would want to apply or explore
once I get home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important part is the 21:00 netplay session. Any match, regardless if I
win or lose, I will save for viewing if I notice something unusual or if a
certain playstyle sticks out that gives me trouble. Really cannot go wrong
when it comes to self-reflection on your own play. I do not immediately watch
these replays. I save them for the mornings. From there, the cycle continues…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ending-thoughts&quot;&gt;Ending thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a bad first week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am looking for in logging my progress are ways to improve the training
process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main components are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A way to capture data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A way to analyze the data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A way to get feedback based on changes you make from analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With saved replays I have come up with a simple cycle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netplay. Save replays that you believe are worth analyzing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study those replays and take notes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return to netplay and apply what you noted. Go to Step 1 as needed 
and repeat the cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without feedback, you are wasting time. How can you tell what to adjust if 
there is nothing to measure your data with?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://glidesu.github.io/2014/05/30/EVO_Training_Week_1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://glidesu.github.io/2014/05/30/EVO_Training_Week_1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Training for EVO 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have finally done it. I have registered for EVO this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/evo2014.png&quot; alt=&quot;EVO 2014 Ticket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training started 2 days ago on May 27, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to play everybody, especially the incoming Japanese
players. Will have plenty of notes prepared for EVO as well as
plenty of notes taken after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot wait!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://glidesu.github.io/2014/05/22/EVO/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://glidesu.github.io/2014/05/22/EVO/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
